

Info



nttps://tisacosta.github.ic



(351) 913644078



teresa.costa@gmail.com



pt.linkedin.com/in/ torosposta



tecanella



Programming

Python SQL SPARQI XML



Datahase:

Virtuosc SDB TDB Redis



RDF OWL Jena Apache Framework Big Data



GNU/Linux MS Windows

R LaTeX Network protocols

TERESA COSTA



Profile

I am a motivated and ambitious person highly interested in new technologies and challenges. I have developed a responsible and mature approach to any task or situation in my professional life. My 4 years of academic research, highly focused in Artificial Intelligence, helped me to develop skills for self-learning and creative thinking as well as skills for software development and solutions to new and unexpected challenges.



Professional Experience

2015 - Now

INESC TEC Porto

R&D on semantic web technologies. This work is part of my phD research (3 publications to date).

Development of a technology to be used on large and huge semantic graphs based on the implementation of semantic similarity and relatedness measures.

This implementation led to the elaboration of an API with that offers the possibility of being accessed through a web interface

Creation of a named-entity dataset using a web-based game

Technologies: Java, Eclipse, GWT, Redis, Junit, CSS, Log4J.

2013 - 2015

Faculdade de Ciências da Universidade do Porto

Researcher @ Faculdade de Ciências da Universidade do Porto. Worked on relational databases, semantic graphs and linked data integration on the project SIBILA ($4\ \rm publications$).

Development of a semantic relatedness algorithm, tuned by bootstrapping and genetic algorithm, to use with semantic graphs

To speed up the algorithm, a graph reduction process, based on its edges, was implemented.

Technologies: Java, Eclipse, Junit, Log4J, Apache Jena Framework, Virtuoso

2010 - 2011

Instituto de Telecomunicações do Porto

Researcher @ Instituto de Telecomunicações do Porto Worked in game, character and interface design on the project LIFEisGAME



Education

Master's Degree in Network and Information Systems Engineering (Communication Networks specialization), Faculdade de Ciências da Universidade do Porto.